Now there are several ways to eliminate ambiguity from a grammar and the most direct
现在有几种方法可以从语法上消除歧义，而最直接的方法
method which we'll talk about first is just to rewrite the grammar so it's an
我们将首先讨论的方法只是重写语法，因此它是一个
ambiguous. That is to write a new grammar that generates the same language as the old
模棱两可。也就是说，编写一个生成与旧语法相同的语言的新语法
grammar but it only has a single Parse tree for each string. So here's a, a rewrite
语法，但是它对每个字符串只有一个解析树。所以这是一个重写
of the grammar we've been looking at and let's write down our favorite input
我们一直在看的语法，让我们写下我们最喜欢的输入
string one more time, id id + id. And let's look at how that string will be parsed
再来一次字符串，id id+id。让我们看看该字符串将如何解析
according to this new grammar so it begin with the start symbol e and now notice
根据这个新语法，它以开始符号e开始，现在请注意
that e can no longer generate a plus or a times. In fact we separated the
e不能再生成加号或乘以。事实上，我们将
grammar now into two sets of productions, two nonterminals and e controls the generation
语法现在分为两组产生式、两个非终结式和e控制式生成
of plus and e prime controls the generation of multiplications, okay. And
加和e的质数控制乘法的产生，好的。和
so in originally of + we have to use the production e prime + e. There is no other
所以在原来的of中，我们必须使用乘积e‘+e，没有其他的。
way to do it. And now if we look at e prime, what can e prime do? Well, e prime
干得好。现在如果我们看看e，能做什么呢？嗯，e素数
can generate an identifier times something and if you look at the grammar that
可以生成一个标识符乘以某物，如果你看一下语法，
is the only production that can generate identifier times something else.
是唯一可以生成标识符乘以其他值的产品。
The only other possibility involving times is to generate apprenticed expression which
涉及时间唯一另一种可能性是生成学徒表达式，该表达式
clearly won't match the string that we're trying to pars E. So we have to use
显然与我们试图解析E的字符串不匹配，所以我们必须使用
this production Id e prime. Well now in order to match the string, we can see that
这部作品的编号是最好的。现在为了匹配字符串，我们可以看到
this e prime, the second, the one remaining e prime here has to go to id because
这个e素数，第二个，这里剩下的一个e素数必须用id表示，因为
sandwiched in between the times and the plus is a single id, there's only
夹在时间和加号之间的是一个单一的id，只有
one production that will do that so that's completely unique and determined. And finally,
一部将做到这一点的作品，因此这是完全独特和坚定的。最后，
we have the last e over here which we want to use to produce an id. Well
我们这里有最后一个e，我们要用它来生成id。井
how can we do that? Well, the e can go to e prime. In fact it has to and then
我们怎么能做到这一点呢？嗯，e可以变成e的质数。事实上，它不得不这样做，然后
the e prime can go to id by itself, and there. We've manage to parse the string. So
e素数可以自己变成id，就在那里。我们已经设法分析了这个字符串。所以
in general what does this grammar doing, well we do say we stratify the grammar.
一般说来，这个语法是做什么的，我们确实说我们把语法分层了。
We've divided the productions into two classes. One that handles times and
我们把这些作品分成两类。一个处理时间和时间的人
one that handles times and there's one nonterminal for each, each operator so. The
一个处理时间，每个操作符都有一个非终结符。这个
e productions control the generation of plus and let's just look at what happens
E产品控制着加号的生成，让我们来看看会发生什么
with that. So if I, e can go to e prime + e and just sticking with the e productions,
就凭这一点。所以如果我，e可以去e+e，然后坚持e的制作，
what can happen to this e here? Well, we could do it again, E prime
这里会发生什么事呢？嗯，我们可以再来一次，E总理
+ e prime + e. And if we do it one more time, we'll have e prime + e prime + e prime
如果我们再做一次，我们就会得到
+ e. And in general, I think you see the pattern, we can generate any number of
一般来说，我想你可以看到这个模式，我们可以产生任意数量的
e primes summed together. And finally, that trailing e, there's always one e left
E个素数加在一起。最后，尾随的e，总是剩下一个e
at the end. Eventually that e, when we want to stop generating pluses, has to be
在最后。最终，当我们想要停止产生正数时，e必须是
rewritten to e prime. So in the end, we'll get a sequence of pluses of, of e primes separated
重写为e素数。所以最后，我们会得到e个素数的加号序列
by pluses, okay? That's what e prime can do. I'm sorry, that's what e can
加号，好吗？这就是e总理能做的。我很抱歉，这就是我们能做的
do. Now let's look at what e prime can do. So, e prime. And let's just focus on the first
做。现在让我们看看e素数能做些什么。所以，e质数。我们只关注第一个
two productions. As we can see at the first two productions are handling identifiers
两部作品。正如我们在前两个产品中看到的那样，它们正在处理标识符
times something and then the last two productions are handling parenthesized
乘以一些东西，然后最后两个结果处理的是括号
expression but you know I hope you the symmetry that it's, it's really
表达，但你知道，我希望你的对称性，它真的
the same idea for identifiers and parenthesized expressions. So we'll just do
标识符和带括号的表达式也是如此。所以我们就这么做
identifiers just to keep the slide from getting too crowded. So e prime can go to
标识符只是为了防止幻灯片变得太拥挤。所以e质数可以转到
id e p rime. Well, we can repeat that, we can go to id. id e prime and we can repeat
我认出了我的名字。嗯，我们可以重复一遍，我们可以去找身份证。我是素数，我们可以重复
that again and I hope you're beginning to see the same pattern. This is
我希望你们开始看到同样的模式。这是
the same idea as with plus. And when we wind up with n is a bunch of identifiers multiplied
与加号的概念相同。当我们最终得到n是一串标识符乘以
together, alright. Because that trailing e prime in this case, in the end,
一起来，好吗。因为在这种情况下，最后的e素数，
can be rewritten to id. Now, in the case of e prime there are actually two alternatives.
可以重写为id。现在，在e素数的情况下，实际上有两种选择。
We could either be generating id's or we could be generating
我们可以生成id，也可以生成
parenthesized expression. So really, for each of these id's it could have been a parenthesized
带括号的表达式。所以说真的，这些id的每一个都可以用括号括起来
expression. So let me just write some parenthesized e's down here just
表达式。所以让我在下面写几个带括号的e
to remind us that we have an alternative and in the end, we wind up with,
提醒我们有另一种选择，最终，我们会得到，
you know? A string of identifiers or parenthesized expressions separated by times,
你知道?由时间分隔的标识符串或带括号的表达式，
Okay? Alright right, so I hope you see how this works. There's the, the way that
好吧?好的，好的，我希望你们能看到这是怎么回事。有一种，有一种方式，就是
the grammar set up because we have these two separate groups of productions.
语法之所以成立，是因为我们有这两组不同的产品。
All the pluses must be generated Before any of the times. The times are gonna be nested
所有的加号都必须在任何时候之前产生。时代将会是嵌套的
more deeply inside the Parse tree than the pluses. The pluses are generated
比加号更深入分析树的内部。产生了加号
at the outer most level and then the e primes will generate the times inside the
在最外层，然后e素数将在
pluses. And so the grammar enforces that times is gonna buy more tightly than plus.
加号。所以语法规定，乘以比加买得更紧。
The last detail that's worth pointing out here is I've noticed inside of the parenthesized
这里值得指出的最后一个细节是，我注意到括号内
expression, we have an e, not an e prime. And why is that? Well once
表达式，我们有e，而不是e素数。为什么会这样呢？嗯，有一次
we're inside of a parenthesized expression, the whole purpose of parentheses
我们在一个带括号的表达式中，括号的全部用途
is to show the explicit association and so that we can have pluses
就是显示明确的关联，这样我们就可以有加号
inside of times by using parentheses. And that's all that, that, that's the significance
在时间内使用括号。这就是所有的，这，这就是意义所在
of using e in this part of the grammar rather than e prime. To review,
在语法的这一部分使用e而不是e质数。回顾一下，
We started out with a grammar and A string we wanted to parse, id id + id, but
我们从语法和我们想要解析的字符串(id、id+id)开始，但是
that grammar gave us two distinct Parse trees for the string and here are the
该语法为字符串提供了两个截然不同的解析树，下面是
two Parse trees again. And by rewriting the grammar, we were able to eliminate
又是两棵解析树。通过重写语法，我们能够消除
this Parse tree on the right. So, this Parse tree is no longer p ossible.
右边的这棵解析树。因此，此解析树不再可行。
The Parse tree on the left is modified, there's more symbols in it now.
左边的解析树被修改了，现在里面有更多的符号。
I mean for example, this became an e prime and there was a chain here of non-terminals,
我的意思是，例如，这变成了一个e质数，这里有一个非终结点的链条，
this e went to e prime and went to id and there was some other minor
这个e转到了e质数，转到了id，还有一些其他的小调。
changes in here so the Parse tree is not exactly the same as before but. We were able
此处的更改使解析树与以前不完全相同，但是。我们能够
to get a parse where the times binds more tightly than the plus. So, now let's
以获得时间比加号更紧密绑定的解析。那么现在让我们
consider another interesting example. If, then, else expressions were the else is optional
考虑另一个有趣的例子。那么，如果ELSE表达式是可选的，则ELSE是可选的
and here's one way to write that grammar. Here we have a if, then, else And
这里有一种写语法的方法。在这里，我们有一个如果，然后，否则
the usual way. But then we also have a production where there is no else. So that's
就像往常一样。但是我们也有一部没有其他作品的作品。所以这就是
the case where the else is optional and then maybe there are some other kinds
在这种情况下，Else是可选的，然后可能会有一些其他类型
of expressions that we don't need to concern ourselves with those. We'll just focus
一系列我们不需要关心的表达方式。我们只需要集中精力
on the if and else piece. The problem is, at this particular if, then, else
在IF和ELSE部分。问题是，在这个特定的如果，那么，否则
expression has two possible Parse tree. On the one hand, the else might belong
表达式有两种可能的解析树。一方面，其他的可能属于
to the outer if, That is, this particular. Inner if might have no else and.
到外面，如果，也就是，这个特殊的。内在的如果可能没有其他的和。
The else would be associated with the outer if. The other possibility is that the
ELSE将与外部IF相关联。另一种可能性是
else belongs to the inner if that we have this structure if then else is nested
Else属于内部，如果我们有这个结构，如果Else是嵌套的
inside of an if then that has no else statement. And in, what we want in on the
在If Then内部，它没有Else语句。在这里面，我们想要的是
programming language I know of is the second form. We want else's to associate to
我知道的编程语言是第二种形式。我们想要将其他的关联到
the closest matching if then and not one that's further away. We can write a grammar
最接近的匹配，如果是这样的话，而不是更远的匹配。我们可以写一本语法
to express the desired association. The property we want is that
来表达想要的联想。我们想要的财产是
every else should match the closest unmatched then. So whenever we see an else,
那么所有其他的都应该匹配最接近的无与伦比的。所以每当我们看到另一个，
we want it to be associated with the closest then that doesn't already have a closer
我们希望它与最接近的相关联，而不是已经有更近的
matching else. So that means that the if statements are going to be divided
与其他的相匹配。这意味着if语句将被分割
into two categories. We'll have the matched if's, those that have all of the then
分为两类。我们会有匹配的IF，那些有所有THEN的
statements nested within them matched with an else. And the unmatched if's where
其中嵌套的语句与Else匹配。和无与伦比的如果在哪里
some then's then expression inside of the unmatched if that has no matching else. So,
一些THEN的THEN表达式位于未匹配的If中，如果没有匹配的其他表达式。所以,
when matched ifs look like, well tha t's pretty straight forward, I, and if, then,
当匹配的if看起来像是，嗯，这是相当直截了当的，我，如果，那么，
else is a matched if most have, must have both of them and an else and any nested
Else是匹配的，如果大多数都有，则必须同时具有它们和Else以及任何嵌套的
if statements on both branches must, must also have matching else's. And,
如果两个分支上的语句都必须，也必须具有与其他语句匹配的语句。
if you have any other kind of a constructs that's not an if and else, that's also considered
如果您有任何其他类型的a结构，而不是if和Else，这也是可以考虑的
a matched if. What about the unmatched if's? One possibility is that they,
一个匹配的如果。那无与伦比的如果呢？一种可能是他们，
it's simply an unmatched if, that there is no else. So we have if and then and
这简直是一个无与伦比的如果，那就是没有其他的了。所以我们有如果和然后
no matching else out here. And now the crucial case, what if we have an if and else?
这里没有比得上的了。现在关键的情况是，如果我们有一个“如果”和“否则”呢？
So that the top level if then has a matching else but then the unmatched if is
因此顶层IF THEN有一个匹配的ELSE，但是不匹配的IF是
somewhere inside. Well, then we claim that the unmatched if has to be in the else branch,
在里面的某个地方。嗯，那么我们认为不匹配的if必须在Else分支中，
it cannot be in the then branch. The then branch must be a matched if. And
它不能在THEN分支中。THEN分支必须是匹配的IF。和
why is that? Well, think about it. If this was an unmatched if, if this was an unmatched
为什么会这样呢？嗯，想想看。如果这是一个无与伦比的如果，如果这是一个无与伦比的
if, that means that there will be some then in here. That had no matching
如果，那就意味着这里会有一些。没有与之相匹配的
else. And then this else here would be closer to that then, than it is to this end
其他的。然后，这里的其他地方就会比这一端更接近那里
then. And so, we would have to match that one according to our definition. Okay.
然后。因此，根据我们的定义，我们必须匹配那个。好吧。
So, that situation is not possible. So, the only possibility for an unmatched
所以，这种情况是不可能的。所以，对于一个无与伦比的人来说，唯一的可能性是
if is that, that it's itself and if and else is that, that the any if, then, else's
如果是这样，那就是它本身，如果和否则是那样，那就是任何如果，那么，其他人的
under their branch have to be matched and the unmatched if and else has
在它们的分支下必须匹配，而不匹配的IF和ELSE
to be in the else branch. So reconsidering the expression we had before, we can see that
在Else分部工作。所以重新考虑我们之前的表述，我们可以看到
this else is supposed to match this then. And so the association should be like
其他的应该和这个相配。所以这个协会应该是这样的
this, and, and therefore, this Parse tree on the right is not the one that we want
因此，右侧的这棵解析树不是我们想要的树
and the grammar we gave on the previous slide will parse the expression according
我们在上一张幻灯片中给出的语法将根据
to this Parse tree on the left.
到左边的这棵解析树。